Do you usually go dutch when you take someone out to dinner?
你通常会在带某人出去吃饭时AA制吗？
Do you expect your date to pay for the whole meal?
你会期望你的约会对象支付整顿饭的费用吗？
Many people say that as long as there's love, money doesn't matter much.
许多人说，只要有爱，钱并不重要。
But this might change when the relationship gets serious and it can involve mortgages, joint current accounts and debt.
但当关系变得认真时，这种情况可能会改变，可能会涉及抵押贷款、联名活期账户和债务。
A survey in the UK suggested that 44% of married couples don't know exactly what their spouse earns.
英国的一项调查显示，44%的已婚夫妇不知道配偶的确切收入。
The research, conducted by a UK credit report service also found that an astonishing 1.9 million married couples actively try to keep their finances secret from their partners.
这项由英国信用报告服务机构进行的研究还发现，令人震惊地是居然有190万对已婚夫妇刻意试图向伴侣隐瞒财务状况。
British relationship therapist Arabella Russell says: "It's very difficult to talk about money.
英国关系治疗师阿拉贝拉·拉塞尔（Arabella Russell）说：“讨论金钱非常困难。
Often there's guilt, there's shame.
通常会有罪恶和羞耻感。
To start those conversations is complicated.
开始这些对话很复杂。
Money can be about how we value ourselves, how we feel valued.
钱可以关乎我们如何评价自己，以及别人如何评价我们。
It's not just a simple case of talking about hard cash."
这不仅仅是谈论现金的简单问题。”
So if you are in a couple, it might be a good idea to check if you both are on the same page about money before bills pile up on the kitchen table and love flies out of the window.
所以，如果你处于恋爱关系中，在账单堆积在厨房桌上、爱情飞出窗外之前，检查一下你们是否在金钱问题上意见一致可能是个好主意。
When moving in together, couples should not only talk about their personal habits but also about their financial ones.
当同居时，情侣们不仅应该谈论他们的个人习惯，还应该谈论他们的财务习惯。
Arabella Russell has a word of advice: "Accept the fact that in your relationship you might do money differently – there might be a spender there might be a saver.
阿拉贝拉·拉塞尔有一句忠告：“接受这样一个事实，即在你们的关系中，你们可能会以不同的方式对待金钱——可能有一个爱花钱的人，也可能有一个爱储蓄的人。
It's very tempting if your partner does things differently to say they're wrong.
如果你的伴侣做事方式与你不同，你会不自禁地想说他们是错的。
Do it differently but have a budget."
可以有不同的方式，但要有一个预算。”
And now, back to that date…
现在，回到那个约会……
Would you be put off by someone who was attractive but expected you to pay the bill by yourself?
你会被一个很有魅力但期望你自己支付账单的人吓跑吗？
There's food for thought…
这值得深思……